Francisco Gonzalez Lorca

Santiago, Chile 56963449698 francisco.gonzalez.lorca@gmail.com https://radocode.github.io/ https://github.com/radocode

I work as a Fullstack Developer, mainly focused in Javascript. I have experiences working with fintech, retail and transport industries.

I enjoy a lot working and researching on new technologies, with small, simple, yet very effective solutions. My favorite frameworks/libraries/runtimes are Angular 2+ and React.js, but I also know Node.js and .NET (C#).

I love to help and guide people around with my current knowledge, and I am always willing to learn new things. I do a lot of research in order to share it later with everyone whenever I can. Always open to learn a new language or technique!

I like to work under Agile methods and Scrum/Kanban teams as well.

Technical Skills

Likes: javascript typescript reactjs react-redux angular node.js go express c# .net-core vue.js vuetify.js nestjs next.js

Experience

Jun 2021 → Mar 2022 **Backend Developer** – <u>X-Team</u> javascript, reactjs, node.js, cloud, salesforce, angular

Backend Developer role for Rstudio, specializing in Node.js. Worked with Salesforce APIs, OAuth Integration, AWS Lambdas and Step Functions for the Business Automation branch.

Mar 2019 → Jun 2021 **Consultant** – <u>Amaris</u> angular, typescript, javascript, node.js, nestjs, vue.js, vuetify.js, salesforce

Consultant role as a Full-stack developer in Angular 8+, Vue.js, Node.js and Typescript for different clients, including Banking and Transport Services (Consorcio Banking and Sodexo).

- Sodexo: Made in Angular 8+, we had to make a complete overhaul of the company's transport service Movilpass (www.movilpass.cl)
- Consorcio: Consorcio required to be made a Portability Banking web portal, which helps potential new clients to bring their current banking products from other banks to Consorcio.

Frontend was made in Vue.js and deployed in Modyo as the CMS.

Rest APIs were made in NestJS, integrating different services from Consorcio. We used Redis for cache, CI/CD with Gitlab and AWS to host the microservices with Docker and Kubernetes.

The service had cloud integration with AWS Lambda, API Gateway and Salesforce API.

We integrated with the Salesforce API to upload documents and process the portability requests to Consorcio's executives for potential leads.

 $Nov\ 2018 \rightarrow Feb\ 2019\$ **Developer** – <u>Lagash</u> node.js, express, reactjs, sql-server

Full-stack developer for a car insurance company called Tanner, using NodeJS and ReactJS.

- We developed a car insurance backoffice web portal fully hosted in Microsoft Azure.
- Backend was made in Node with Restify, using Azure's cloud databases for storage.
- Frontend was made using React + Redux and Material UI for the components. We had to integrate our microservices made in Node with the frontend app.

Oct 2017 → Aug 2018 Solutions Analyst - Everis

angular, node.js, angular-material

Front-end developer in Angular 2+/NodeJS for BCI (Office Banking), as a part of their Migration and Digital Transformation process.

- We worked in a huge Agile project which involved around five agile squads all working on the same product.
 Dailies and meetings were big!
- My squad had two frontend devs, two backend devs completely dedicated to Spring Boot, one QA person and one Tech Lead to guide us. I was one of the frontend devs.
- We frontend devs had also to develop not only in Angular, but also in the app's BFF (Backend for Frontend) that
 was made in Node, is with Express. Our job was to call the microservices made in Spring Boot and
 process/format the data ready for the frontend to use it.
- Technologies used: Angular 2+ (native, Material) and NodeJS (with Express).

Sep 2015 → Oct 2017 **Developer** – <u>Defontana</u>

c#, .net, asp.net, asp, vbscript, asp.net-mvc

.NET and VB Developer in ERP Products, Continuous Integration, and Backend REST solutions for Defontana's Digital Transformation process.

Technologies used: C#, VB.NET, WCF (microservices), MS Web API, ASP.NET, Razor, SQL Server 2018

Legacy technologies: VB 6, ASP

Apr 2015 → Aug 2015 Backend Developer – <u>Tuten</u> java, jax-rs, postgresql

Backend designer, REST services programmer, Database developer.

- TUTEN is a web/mobile app service that helps people search for professional household services (painting, plumbers, electrical, etc). Works similar to Uber.
- I designed the database and REST services for TUTEN app's first version.
- With the team, we travelled to Boston, USA for 3 months to MassChallenge's 2015 startup accelerator
 conference, to learn how to boost the startup business process and development cycle.

Technologies used: Java, JAX-RS, Postgres SQL

Jan 2011 → Mar 2015 **Developer** – <u>TAISA Chile</u>

c#, java, asp.net, asp, sql-server

Software Developer for web and mobile solutions, using .NET (C#, ASP.NET), Java (EE and WebSphere), SQL Server, PHP, plus maintaining some other legacy software used in Banking made in ASP and Javascript with jQuery. Clients worked with: Santander, SURA, Corpbanca.

Technologies used: C#, Java, ASP.NET, Javascript, jQuery, ASP, SQL Server.

Education

 $\it Jan~2005
ightarrow \it Jan~2010$ Bachelor in Computer Science – DUOC UC java, c#, html, php

Focusing in Microsoft Technologies, and volunteer work in the Microsoft Student Partners program, educational talks in technology to local college.

Others

Jun 2020 Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate – Certification scrum, agile

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate from CertProf

May 2020 React Development Certification Course – Certification reactis

React Development Certification Course from Programming Hub

May 2020 HTML Certification Course – Certification html

HTML Certification Course from Programming Hub

May 2020 **JavaScript Certification Course** – Certification javascript

JavaScript Certification Course from Programming Hub

May 2020 **JavaScript Tutorial Course** – Certification javascript

JavaScript Tutorial Course from SoloLearn

May 2020 **C# Tutorial Course** – Certification c#, .net

C# Tutorial Course from SoloLearn

May 2020 **React + Redux Course** – Certification reactjs, react-redux

React + Redux Course from SoloLearn

May 2020 CSS Certification Course – Certification

CSS Certification Course from Programming Hub

Tools

First Computer: Compaq Presario
Favorite Editor: Visual Studio Code